Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
集中できてないな　まだ体が迷っているんだ
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
震えていたんじゃ　コントロールしたってブレるんだ
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
ツキ
太陽も勝負運もなんも完全にこっち向いていないが
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
「やるしかないんだ」
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
言い聞かせるようにそうつぶやいた
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
状況は悪いが　ただ逃げ出すんじゃ根性ないなぁ
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
展望はないが　度胸でクリアするしかないや
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
衝動は抑えたままターゲットとの間隔探れ
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
必要なもんは勝つプライド
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
味わうのは勝利の美酒か
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
それとも敗北の苦汁か
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
そう　すべては2つに1つ
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
操りたい運命の糸
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
絶好のゴールデンタイム　この手で掴め
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
渾身のポーカーフェイス　キメて仕掛けるよ
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
イリュージョンの世界へ引きずり込んで
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
際限無いプレッシャーゲーム　スルリと抜けて
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
栄光のボーダーライン　飛び越えるために
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
ハウメニー？　どれくらいの代償がいる？
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
手放したくないもんはどれ？
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
Ed and Al were searching for May, a girl from Xing, to find out more about Eastern Alchemy.
錬丹術の秘密を探るため
シンの国の少女メイを捜す　エドとアルは
They are now headed north after learning she was headed in that direction.
彼女が北へ向かったとの情報を手に入れる
一方
At the same time, Kimblee, the Crimson Alchemist, is after Scar, who had just left Central and is now westbound.
セントラルを出発し　西へと向かうスカーを
紅蓮の錬金術師キンブリーが追う
But Scar suddenly disappeared in the darkness of the night.
だが　スカーは夜陰に紛れ
忽然と姿をくらますのだった
If they were to jump off the train, it would surely be around here, where the track is full of curves,
列車から飛び降りるなら
カーブの多いこの辺りでしょう
since the engine would decelerate.
機関車が減速しますからね
問題は　ここからどちらに向かったかですが
Now the question is, where did they go after they jumped off?
スカーの目撃情報は
Have there been any sighting reports on Scar?
None at all, sir...
それがようとして
That's very strange.
変ですね
He had been attracting a lot of attention up until this point.
ここへ来るまでは派手に動き回っていたのに
Reporting in, sir!
報告します　南へ２００メートルほど行った川沿いで
A small boat by the river has been stolen about 200 meters south of here!
小船が１艘盗まれたとのことです
Was it Scar?
スカーか
There haven't been any sightings so far.
今のところ　目撃情報はありません
Go investigate.
調査しろ
Roger!
はっ
Reporting in, sir!
報告します
近所に住む老人が 西へ向かう
We've received a report from an old man, who lives in the area, of two suspicious-looking men heading westbound.
怪しい二人連れの男を目撃したとのことです
Now they're heading west?
今度は西か
Send some men over and capture those two immediately!
すぐに兵をやり　その二人連れを捕らえろ
Roger!
はっ
Is something the matter?
どうかしましたか
No, it's just that...
いえ　ただ
There's a mountain trail on this map that heads north.
この地図　北に向かう山道があるんですが
Why is it crossed out?
これ　なんです
There used to be a path through
the forest to get to the northern area,
ノースエリアに抜ける林道でしたが
落石が絶えず
but it's been closed down due to landslides.
今は通行そのものを禁じています
What about the path, sir?
これが何か
There are several other places beyond this point that have been closed off due to landslides.
この先数か所　ここと同じように
巨大な落石が道をふさいでいます
It looks like the stream has moved.
水の流れが変わっていますね
It seems so... but are you saying it means something?
そのようですが　それが何か
For an alchemist skilled in destruction, removing an obstacle such as this is a walk in the park.
破壊を得意とする錬金術師にとって
この程度の障害物を排除することなど容易い
はっ
It's also simple to destroy the surface of a mountain and to block off the road with the rocks.
同様に
山肌を破壊し落石で再び道をふさぐこともまたしかり
Signs of transmutation?!
錬成の跡
Send the troops north.
兵を北へ
Snow!
雪だ
Brother!
兄さん
痛っ
Geez, you're so fidgety!
もう　兄さんは落ち着きがないんだよ
Shut up, I just slipped.
うっせぇな　ちょっと滑っただけだろ
Man, look at all the snow!
でもほんとすごい雪だね
Yeah. We rarely see snow in Resembool.
ああ　リゼンブールじゃ滅多にお目にかかれない
Oh yeah, Al.
そうだ　アル
Do you remember when it snowed heavily in Resembool when we were kids?
ちっちゃい時のリゼンブールの大雪　覚えてるか
Heavy snowfall?
大雪
Oh, I remember now!
覚えてる覚えてる
We had a snowball fight!
みんなで雪合戦した
We made a snowman, too, remember?
雪だるまも作ったな
Yeah!
うん
Back then, I never would have thought that I'd come this far north...
子供のころは
自分がこんな北の果てに来るなんて
思ってもみなかったけど
ああ　来ちまったな
But we did, didn't we?
Well, what to do now?
さて　どうする
We've still got time until the train to Briggs departs.
ブリッグズ行きの列車が出るまで
まだ時間があるぞ
Why don't you go eat something nice?
何かおいしいものでも食べなよ
I'm not really hungry...
腹は減ってねぇけど
But I guess I'll go see what's on the menu!
まっ　とにかく行ってみるか
走ったらまた転ぶよ
Hey! If you start running, you'll slip again!
うっせぇ
Shut up!
Yes. Three hours ago...
ノースエリア各所に伝達
Scar's description, document number, and...
スカーの人相書きは　書類番号…
何か情報は
Any new information so far?
We're trying our best, but we haven't found anything yet.
全力で捜索中でありますが
申し訳ありません
１つ先の駅の操車場で
A man matching Scar's description was sighted at the marshalling yard at the next station.
スカーらしき男が目撃されました
Is this confirmed?
間違いないのか
Yes, sir.
間違いありません
He was last seen climbing into
a troop transport headed for Briggs.
ブリッグズ行きの軍用列車に乗り込んだところを
目撃したとのことです
同行者は
Was there anyone with him?
A middle-aged man with black hair.
中年男性で髪は黒
Matches the initial report perfectly.
報告書どおりです
すぐに列車を止めさせます
We'll have the train stopped immediately.
There's no need for that.
その必要はありません
It would be troublesome if they leap off again.
また飛び降りられても困りますから
I'll take over from here.
さて
ここからは私の仕事です
Please don't interfere with my work.
あなたたちは邪魔をしないように
Sleep for now.
眠っておけ
When we get further north, you'll have
a hard time sleeping because of the cold.
北の寒さの中では　眠りたくても眠れんぞ
I'm jumping over. Please try to match the speed of the other train.
飛び移ります　速度を合わせてください
Yes, sir!
了解です
Dr. Marcoh.
ドクター·マルコー　お迎えに上がりました
I've come to pick you up.
You've got nowhere else to run.
もう逃げられませんよ
Are you alone?
お一人ですか　スカーはどこに
Where is Scar?
You just don't know when to quit, do you?
往生際が悪い
逃げられないと言ったでしょう
Didn't I just say you had nowhere else to run, Doctor Mar-
ドクター·マル…
誰
Who are you?
So you're the Ishbalan everyone's talking about...
あなたが噂のイシュヴァール人ですか
You can't expect me to put up with those monsters!
あんな化け物どもにつきあってられるか
Now's my chance to jump off...
飛び降りるなら　今のうち
Impossible...
無理
Solf J. Kimblee. The Crimson Alchemist.
ゾルフ·Ｊ·キンブリー
紅蓮の錬金術師
Do you remember me?
オレを覚えているか
Yes. Very clearly, in fact.
ええ　よく覚えていますよ
あなた　イシュヴァールのカンダ地区にいた
You were in the Kanda district of Ishbal.
Was it your family that was around you at the time?
あの時あなたの周りにいたのはご家族
I believe there was someone who closely resembled you, but with glasses.
あなたそっくりで眼鏡を掛けた方がいましたっけね
Bleeding heavily from his left abdomen...
左脇腹から大量の血を流し
...and writhing in pain...
大層な苦もんの
This isn't good.
まずいですね
I'm rusty from being in jail for all this time, but he's been fighting since the civil war.
こちらは出所したばかりで体がなまっているのに
あちらは内乱の後も戦い続けてきた
In terms of stamina, I'm at a disadvantage.
体力的にはこちらが不利
だが　しょせんは壊すことしか
However, all he can do is destroy-
左脇腹だったな
Left abdomen, was it?
I won't give you the time to pray.
神に祈る間はやらん
It's... a shame...
残念　ですね
That I'd fail to kill the same Ishbalan twice...
同じイシュヴァール人を二度もしとめ損ねるとは
How humiliating that I have to run away...
この私が逃げとは　とてつもない屈辱ですよ
We'll settle the match next time, Ishbalan!
次は必ずケリをつけましょう
イシュヴァール人
Kimblee!!!
キンブリー
Dammit, I can't see!
畜生　見えねぇ
What the hell was that noise?
なんだったんだ　さっきの音は
One of the cars is missing!
後ろの車両がねぇ
We can't! We've been ordered by the army not to stop the train!
まずいですよ
止めるなって軍の命令が出てます
いや　ダメだ
No, we have to!
It'll be our fault if the train derails!
脱線事故でも起こしたら
こっちの責任問題になる
What... happened to you?!
あんた　何があった　おい
Hey!
誰が　止めていいと言った
Who the hell said you could stop the train?!
What?!
Keep the train running.
このまま走らせろ　北へ向かえ
Head north!
Good... death is chasing me.
いいぞ　そうだ
死が迫ってくる
Ones who kill are also chased by death.
死を築く者は　死に追われるのだ
Always living alongside death...
常に死と隣り合わせ
Jobs that risk one's soul are truly beautiful!
魂を懸ける仕事こそ　美しさがある
How rewarding...
なんとやり応えのある　私の戦場
My battlefield!
I wonder if Mr. Scar and Mr. Yoki are all right?
スカーさんとヨキさん　大丈夫でしょうか
Since no one has come after us yet, it must mean they're doing a good job drawing the army's attention.
私たちに追っ手がないということは
うまく　憲兵の目を引いてくれているのだろうね
I hope they're safe.
無事だといいが
Dr. Marcoh?
マルコーさん
No, it's just that...
いや
治りかけの皮膚に　北国の風はこたえる
The northern wind is painful against healing skin.
Sorry. I wish I could have healed it to make it look a little better...
ご免なさい
もう少し格好のいい顔に治せればよかったんですけど
No, the face fits me well.
いや　私には分相応な顔だ
I'm happy with it.
満足している
Take a look, May.
メイちゃん　見てごらん
Wow!
They're the Briggs Mountains.
ブリッグズ山脈だ
The mountain range that serves as the border between our country and Drakma.
北の大国　ドラクマとの国境になる山々だよ
We should be close to the location Scar pointed out...
そろそろ　スカーが示した場所に近いはずだが
Let's see...
えっと
あっ　もうすぐそこです
We're almost there!
え　ホテル引き揚げちゃったんですか
Huh? He checked out of the hotel?
Yes, just yesterday.
はい　昨日のうちに
Do you know where he went?
どこに行ったか分かります
確か　北へ行くとおっしゃってましたが
If I recall correctly, he said that they were headed north...
そうですか　お世話さま
I see...
Thanks.
あのバカ
That idiot...
どうしたの　兄弟は元気だった
What's wrong? Were they doing well?
あのまま北へ行ったって
He said they headed north in that state.
あらまぁ　それは
Oh, my! He's totally...
死ぬわね
...gonna die.
兄さん風邪
Did you catch a cold, Brother?
うぅ寒い　さすがブリッグズ
So cold...
It's Briggs, all right.
ここだよ　あんちゃんたち
We're here, boys.
この山道を道なりに行けば
If you follow this mountain path, you'll get to the Briggs fortress.
ブリッグズ要塞に出る
Thanks.
ありがとう
Oh yeah, you.
あっそうだ　君
Me?
そう君　それ機械鎧
Yeah, you.
That's not an automail, is it?
いいえ
Nope.
Oh. Then you should be fine.
ああそう　だったらいいんだ
What was that about?
どうした
さあ
No idea.
その柵の向こうは軍の所有地だから
Everything beyond that fence is owned by the army,
so you'll die if you stray from the path!
道から外れたら死ぬよ
Huh?
はい？
行くか
Let's go!
うん
Yeah.
山の天気は変わりやすいっていうが
They say the weather changes rapidly in the mountains, but I never expected something like this...
こんな急に変わるとは
どうしよう　兄さん
What should we do, Brother?
We've completely lost our way.
完全に道を見失ったよ
Don't worry!
安心しろ
Master Izumi was thrown into the Briggs Mountains in the winter for a month for her training, and she still survived.
イズミ師匠は修行時代
冬のブリッグズ山に１か月ほうり込まれても
生還したらしいぞ
うそだ
There's no way that could be true!
How could someone survive for a month out here?!
こんな中で１か月も生き延びられるわけがない
But she said she defeated a bear, too!
でも　熊も倒したって
ブリッグズの熊は
The bears at Briggs grow to a height of up to two meters!
立ち上がったら２メートルを越えるんだよ
そんなの倒せるわけないじゃ
Who'd be able to defeat one?
熊っ
A bear!!!
熊じゃない
That's not a bear!
アル
Al!
おい　待てって
Hey, hang on!
You're wearing a military uniform!
国軍の軍服じゃねぇか
貴様も機械鎧か　ただの平凡な
You have an automail, too?
Just an ordinary one, it seems.
ああ　そっちこそ趣味悪いの付けてんじゃねぇか
Yours is just plain ugly!
How foolish of you to not understand the beauty of this arm!
この機械美が分からんとは愚か者め
戦闘用機械鎧Ｍ１９１３－Ａクロコダイル
Combat Model Automail M1913-A Crocodile.
かみちぎられたくなかったらおとなしく捕まれ
Surrender if you don't want to be ripped to shreds, Drakman spy!
ドラクマの密偵め
密偵
Spy?
何言ってんだ　オレは…
What the hell are you talking about? I'm...
Why, you...
この
話分かんねぇデカ物だな
Can't you be a little more understanding, oaf?
なんだこの痛みは
What is this pain?
機械鎧がうまく動かねぇ
My automail isn't moving very well!
You're mine!
うお　取ったり
兄さん
Brother!
この野郎
You bastard...
Just listen to me!
人の話聞けって
You're still going to resist?!
まだ逆らうか
うっ　うそ
Are you serious?!
Wait! Wait! Wait! Just listen!!
待て待て待て待て　待てって
Your useless automail is mine!
なまくら機械鎧もらった
More like, your  arm is mine!
この　もらうのは　てめぇの腕だ
Did you do something?
何かしたか
うわぁ　ちょっとたんまたんまたんまマジたんま
Time out! Time out! Time out! Seriously! Time out!
なんで錬金術が効かねぇんだよ
Why doesn't alchemy work?!
これ鉄じゃねぇのかよ
This isn't made out of iron?!
Brother!
兄さん
Thanks, Al!
サンキュー　アル
大丈夫
Are you okay?
野郎
That freak...
雪山で死ぬ前にウィンリィに殺されるじゃねぇか
I would've been killed by Winry before I froze to death out here.
やるな　小僧
Not bad, brat.
You did well for having a regular automail.
ノーマルの機械鎧でよく頑張った
But this is it for you.
だがここまでだ
What?
ブリッグズの山岳警備兵
Security personnel from Briggs?!
おいおい　また銃突きつけられかよ
Geez, at gunpoint again?
兄さん
Brother.
壁
A wall?
What's the matter, Captain Buccaneer?!
どうした　バッカニア大尉
はっ　お騒がせして申し訳ありません
I'm sorry for causing such a commotion, Major General Armstrong!
アームストロング少将閣下
アームストロングって
Armstrong?
So that's the person Major Armstrong wanted to introduce to us...
あれがアームストロング少佐が紹介するって言ってた
オリヴィエ·ミラ·アームストロング
...Olivier Mira Armstrong?
Major Armstrong's sister!
アームストロング少佐の姉ちゃん
でも
But...
似てない
She looks nothing like him.
She's not huge.
でかくない
貴様　何者だ
Who the hell are you?
鋼の錬金術師　エドワード·エルリック
Edward Elric, the Fullmetal Alchemist.
セントラルのアームストロング少佐の紹介で
I came to see you, Major General, with a letter of introduction from Major Armstrong from Central.
こちらの少将閣下に会いに来た
Please get these guys off of us, first!
まずこの警備兵をどけてほしい
ボディーチェックをしろ
Perform a full body check!
んなっ　怪しい者じゃないって
What?!
We're not suspicious in the least bit!
知らん
How should I know?
有名人の名をかたることなど　誰でもできる
Anyone can pretend to be someone well-known.
What?! There's no one in here?!
うおっ空っぽ
にゃろう
That bitch...
Hm? This is...
ん　これは
閣下
Ma'am!
それはアレックス·ルイ·アームストロング少佐
That's the letter from Major Alex Louis Armstrong.
からの紹介状だ
読んでくれれば
If you read it, you'll know that we're not suspicious at all.
オレたちが怪しい者じゃないと分かる
確かにアレックスだ
It really is from Alex.
読んでくれねぇのかよ
You're not even going to read it?!
Testimonials mean nothing to me.
紹介状など私には無意味だ
私以外の他人がつけた評価なぞいらん
I don't need assessments made by others.
私は私の目で人を判断する
I'll judge you with my own eyes.
すっ　すげぇ
A-Amazing.
でっけぇ　なんだこれ
It's huge...
What the hell is this?!
入れ　鋼の錬金術師
Come in, Fullmetal Alchemist.
Awesome! It's so tall! It's huge!
すげぇ　高ぇ　でけぇ
Hurry up and walk, laggards.
とっとと歩かんかグズども
Want me to rip that antenna off your head?
頭の上のアンテナむしり取るぞ
先に言っておくが子供扱いはせん
I'll tell you this now. I won't be treating you like a kid.
ここは天険の地　ブリッグズ
This is Briggs, the land of natural defense.
弱肉強食の世界だ
A world where the weak are victims of the strong.
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
朝日が昇るまで語り合ったね
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
夕陽が沈むまでつないだ手
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
こうやって明日も明後日も共に歩もう光と影
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
寂しげに見つめる街の中で
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
温もりはひとりじゃ見つからなくて
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
愛がこんなに強さになること
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
知ったんだ　キミに出逢えてはじめて
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
一人じゃ眠れない　夢は見れないから
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
どんな不安も届かないところへ
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
星のない夜も照らし続けよう
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
何処までも行けるキミとなら
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
一人じゃ歩けない道も二人なら
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
鼻歌歌いながら歩けるんだ
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
キミがいれば幸せ
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
あった
There it is!
これがスカーの兄の研究書
So these are his brother's research documents.
シンの錬丹術と
A combination of the alchemies from Xing and Amestris.
アメストリスの錬金術を融合させたものですね
不老不死の法は載っているでしょうか
I wonder if there's anything about immortality in here?
載ってるといいね
I hope there is.
これが希望の書となるか
Now, will this become a book of hope,
or will it turn out to be a book of despair...
はたまた絶望の書となるか
さあ　解読を始めよう
Let's begin the analysis.
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
ブリッグズの将軍
The general of Briggs, Olivier Mira Armstrong.
オリヴィエ·ミラ·アームストロング
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
激しく　強く　北を統べるアメストリスの守護神
Fierce and powerful, she is Amestris' guardian of the north.
恐れはない　恐れられることはあっても
She has no fears, though there are many that fear her.
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第三十四話　氷の女王
Episode 34, Ice Queen.
ブリッグズ流を見るがいい
This is how we do things in Briggs.